<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- application labels -->
    <string name="app_name">Tip Calculator</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="txt_num">1</string>
    <string name="txt_zero_dollar">$0.00</string>
    <string name="txt_percent">%1$s\%%</string>
    <string name="txt_percent_default">15\%%</string>
    <string name="txt_poor">Poor</string>
    <string name="txt_fair">Fair</string>
    <string name="txt_good">Good!</string>
    <string name="txt_great">Great!</string>
    <string name="txt_royal">Royal!</string>
    <string name="txt_service">Service:</string>
    <string name="txt_title">Tip Calculator</string>
    <string name="txt_creators">by Leonard Tatum &amp; Kazuya Shibuta</string>
    <string name="txt_bill">Bill: $</string>
    <string name="txt_tip">Tip Amount:</string>
    <string name="txt_shared">Shared By:</string>
    <string name="txt_person">Each Person Pays:</string>
    <string name="txt_total">Total Bill Amount:</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_dollar">0.00</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_integer">0</string>
    <string name="txt_round_on">Round On:</string>
    <string name="txt_round_off">Round Off:</string>
    <string name="txt_spinner_default">Select Tip Percent</string>
    <string name="btn_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="btn_guide">Tip Guide</string>
    <string name="btn_inc">+</string>
    <string name="btn_dec">-</string>
    <string name="txt_shake">Shake to reset feature currently disabled. To enable, go to Settings</string>

    <!-- location services -->
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="enable_location_services_message">%s needs access to your location to better
		track your history. Please turn on location services.</string>

    <!-- headers -->
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy</string>
    <string name="guide">Guide</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="setting">Settings</string>

    <!-- history -->
    <string name="not_applicable">N/A</string>
    <string name="bill_amount">Total Bill Amount $%1$s</string>
    <string name="no_history">No history found. Make sure \'Save History\' is enabled in Settings</string>
    <string name="tip_percent">Tip Percent %1$s\%%</string>
    <string name="tip_amount">Tip Amount $%1$s</string>
    <string name="tip_amount_week">Tip Amount For the Week: $%1$s</string>
    <string name="avg_tip_percentage_week">Average Tip Percentage For the Week: %1$s\%%</string>
    <string name="avg_tip_percentage_overall">Average Tip Percentage Overall: %1$s\%% (%2$s)</string>
    <string name="day_date">%1$s - %2$s</string>
    <string name="location">%1$s</string>
    <string name="tip_quality">Tip Quality: %1$s</string>

    <!-- guide -->
    <string name="required">Required</string>
    <string name="not_required">Not Required</string>

    <!-- guide countries -->
    <string name="australia">Australia</string>
    <string name="bahamas">Bahamas</string>
    <string name="canada">Canada</string>
    <string name="china">China</string>
    <string name="cuba">Cuba</string>
    <string name="dominican_republic">Dominican Republic</string>
    <string name="france">France</string>
    <string name="germany">Germany</string>
    <string name="ghana">Ghana</string>
    <string name="jamaica">Jamaica</string>
    <string name="japan">Japan</string>
    <string name="kenya">Kenya</string>
    <string name="mexico">Mexico</string>
    <string name="niger">Niger</string>
    <string name="spain">Spain</string>
    <string name="united_kingdom">United Kingdom</string>
    <string name="united_states">United States</string>

    <!-- guide descriptions -->
    <string name="guide_australia">There isn\'t a rule when it comes to tipping in Australia.
		Traditionally, tourism industry employees get paid enough that they don\'t need a tip.
		\n\nLocals will tell you not to tip, but it has become more common as a result of Americans
		traveling to the country.\n\nIf you are in a really nice restaurant or bar or any tourist
		spot, you can tip 10\%%-15\%%.</string>
    <string name="guide_bahamas">Tipping is expected in these islands, and you should tip
		according to the quality of service.\n\nBellboys and porters usually receive $1-$2 per bag,
		while most other servers, e.g. waiters, taxis, ect receive 15\%%.</string>
    <string name="guide_canada">Gratuities are seldom included in Canadian restaurants, so it is
		up to you to provide the tip.\n\nIt\'s customary to tip approximately 15-20\%% on the total
		bill before tax, less for poor service, more for truly exceptional service.\n\nMany restaurants,
		may charge an automatic 15\%%-18\%% gratuity for larger groups.</string>
    <string name="guide_china">If you are dining or drinking somewhere local, there is no need to tip.\n\n
		If you are at a nicer establishment, you might notice a 10\%%-15\%% service charge added to your
		bill. There is no need to tip anything in addition to that.\n\nBe careful how you use your
		chopsticks. For example, it is rude to stand them upright in your rice bowl or point them
		at someone else.</string>
    <string name="guide_cuba">It\'s a good idea to have a few 1 CUC notes on hand when staying in a
		hotel. When your bags are carried to your room, a 1 CUC tip is acceptable. You might be in
		the habit of leaving a tip for your maid on the day you check out, but when tipping in Cuba,
		it\'s more appropriate to level 1 CUC for the maid each day.</string>
    <string name="guide_dominican_republic">Tipping is very appreciated in the DR (Dominican Republic),
		as wages are extremely low. A dollar to them goes a long way. Guests can leave small items
		and usually $1 to $2 each morning on the pillows for the maids and just add a little note to
		let them know that it is for them.</string>
    <string name="guide_france">Your bill will include a 15\%% service charge, but locals usually tip 10\%%
		on top of that.\n\nLooking to save some coin? Just remember there is no need to tip at bars!
		\n\nSplitting the bill is considered unsophisticated in France, so always offer to pay the
		whole bill.</string>
    <string name="guide_germany">Round up to the nearest euro and consider this their tip, especially
		when ordering only one item, like a drink.\n\nIf you want to leave a more substantial tip
		(for a larger meal), leave 10\%%-15\%%, and let your service know what you are tipping before you
		pay.\n\nWater or bread served at restaurants is not free. Asking for tap water is uncommon and
		frowned upon; the service will often turn down your request.</string>
    <string name="guide_ghana">The way money is used and talked about in Ghana may be very different
		from what you are used to. Be prepared for people asking you for money, bargaining in shops
		and make sure you leave a tip for good service!\n\nAlthough it is not protocol to tip,
		generally a tip is expected and always appreciated. It is customary to leave a tip for the
		maid so that he or she cleans your hotel room properly, and when someone goes out of their
		way to help you, for example, giving you directions.\n\nAs words of caution, do not be overly
		generous, as this may appear that you are flaunting money.</string>
    <string name="guide_jamaica">Employees at no tipping resorts can lose their job for accepting
		gifts or tips. Taxis in Jamaica are mainly non-metered, which means you set the price with
		the driver before boarding the taxi. It\'s OK to leave a tip during this time.</string>
    <string name="guide_japan">Tipping is not mandatory or expected.\n\nOffering a cash tip to a
		waiter is rude and doing so may cause confusion. If you feel the need to tip, put the yen in
		a small envelope and give it directly to your server.\n\nDo not be afraid to audibly slurp
		noodles here; it\'s though to help the eater enjoy the dish more and improve the flavor.</string>
    <string name="guide_kenya">For more structured services, a 100 shilling (roughly $1) tip would
		be fair enough. At hotels, porters can be tipped anything from 50 shillings to 100 shillings.
		\n\nYou may give your housekeeper anything from 200 shillings to 500 shillings per week to
		ensure motivation and good service by her.</string>
    <string name="guide_mexico">At restaurants, it is customary to leave a 10\%%-15\%% tip.\n\nIf there is
        an amount listed as "IVA" on your bill, that\'s 16\%% of your bill, so you can also tip that
        instead.\n\nSometimes the tip will be included in your restaurant bill, so there will be no
        need to leave any additional tip.\n\nIt\'s completely acceptable to eat with your hands here.</string>
    <string name="guide_niger">Tipping is appreciated in Niger and, while a service charge is
        generally added to restaurant bills, extra tips are still appreciated. Taxi drivers, tour
        guides, barmen and porters all take tips.\n\n10\%% tip is customary. Be careful with
        over tipping as you may draw unwanted, and even dangerous, attention to yourself.</string>
    <string name="guide_spain">Locals tip very modestly, leaving behind small change or rounding up
		to the nearest Euro is common. However, if you are happy with your service, you should tip
		between 7\%%-15\%% in cash.</string>
    <string name="guide_united_kingdom">Tipping is not expected in the UK in the way it is in other
		countries. However, a small tip is still considered a nice gesture. If you tip between 10\%%
		and 12\%% you are too kind. This is enough to display your generosity and satisfaction with
		the service.</string>
    <string name="guide_united_states">For waiters at sit-down restaurants, bartenders, barbers,
		hair-dressers, taxi drivers, tour guides, and food delivery, the tip should be calculated
		as a percentage of your total bill. Tip 10\%% if you are not completely happy. 15\%% indicates
		that the service was acceptable. And 20\%% means the service was really good.</string>

    <!-- about -->
    <string name="follow_me">Follow Me:</string>
    <string name="copyright_year">Copyright %s, Leonard Tatum. All Rights Reserved.</string>
    <string name="about_desc">This app is 100\%% free, created for the education, convenience
		and use of the public. There will never be in-app purchases or alternative paid versions
		of the app. To learn about other apps Leonard Tatum is working on, connect with him on social
		media or send him an email with your questions or comments. Cheers!</string>
    <string name="feedback_email">For feedback or support, contact\n Leonard Tatum at
		<a href="mailto:ljtatum@hotmail.com">ljtatum@hotmail.com</a></string>

    <!-- privacy -->
    <string name="privacy_desc">Leonard Tatum is committed to protecting your privacy and
	providing the best user experience possible. This is why data collected will never be sold
	or traded to others. \n\nInformation collected may be used to (i) remember information so
	you will not have to re-enter it during your session or the next sessions you are using the
	Service (ii) provide personalize content and information to you and others, which could
	include online ads or other forms or marketing (iii) provide, improve, test and monitor the
	effectiveness of our Service (iv) develop and test new products and features (v) diagnose or
	fix bugs and issues.</string>

    <!-- settings -->
    <string name="customize_preferences">Customize Your Preferences</string>
    <string name="settings_save_history">Save History: %s</string>
    <string name="settings_save_location">Save Location: %s</string>
    <string name="settings_shake">Shake To Reset: %s</string>
    <string name="settings_round_off">Default Round Off: %s</string>
    <string name="settings_set_default_tip">Set Default Tip%:</string>
    <string name="settings_set_default_shared_by">Set Default Shared By:</string>
    <string name="settings_enabled">Enabled</string>
    <string name="settings_disabled">Disabled</string>
    <string name="settings_save_history_info">Enabling this feature will track your tipping history</string>
    <string name="settings_save_location_info">Enabling this feature will track where you are tipping!
		Save History and Location Services must both be enabled</string>

    <!-- guide text -->
    <string name="txt_guide">Q1: Where don’t you tip? 
			\n\nA1: In Japan, this offering is considered offensive! 
			Because of a tip’s nature as a gift or a favor, it can be 
			perceived as an implication of servility.
			\n\nQ2: Where do you tip? 
			\n\nA2: Pretty much everywhere else! It is never embarrassing 
			to leave a tip on the table. In fact, in countries where it 
			isn’t required it is all the more appreciated. But in the US, 
			tipping is almost a mandatory requirement. This is why it is 
			important to know the rules for tipping. How much do you tip? 
			And what are reasonable tip amounts?
			\n\nQ3: How to determine the tippable total? 
			\n\nA3: Using applications like a Tip Calculator is a wonderful 
			first step to ensuring that you are issuing good tips! But here 
			are a couple unspoken rules. First, if you used any coupons or 
			discounts, calculate the tip based on how much you would have 
			paid without it. Otherwise you are punishing the server for the 
			restaurant management’s efforts to entice you through the front 
			door. For example, if you have a 2-for-1 coupon (two-fer!), you 
			may only have had to pay for half of your meal, but the waiter 
			still did the full amount of work.
			\n\nAlso, if there is a tax on your bill, you should calculate 
			the tip based on the pretax amount, since the service is not 
			really related to the tax. Additionally, the difference between 
			a tip on the total (including tax) and the pretax amount is not 
			significant.
			\n\nQ4: Is how much I tip based on the quality of service? 
			\n\nA4: The answer is yes, and no. The proper etiquette is to tip 
			regardless of terrible service, although doing so is still 
			controversial. Why pay for terrible service, right? The key is to 
			objectively judge the service, and the service alone. If the 
			food is not good, the menu is sparse, the prices are outrageous, 
			and/or the décor is appalling, all of this affects your dining 
			experience, but is not the waiter’s fault. So identify what is 
			in control of your waiter’s hands and what is not. And at the end 
			of the day, have some compassion and practice giving the benefit 
			of the doubt. If the service was not quite stellar, it may not be 
			the waiter’s fault. Exceptions are if your waiter is rude or 
			neglectful! 
			\n\nQ5: How much to tip? 
			\n\nA5: It’s great that you have an application in your hands to 
			help you determine this! No matter how poor the quality of services 
			was, leaving a tip of less than 10\%% will not be looked upon
			favorably nor will it paint you in a very good light, in case of 
			future visits. Tips amounting to 18-20\%% of the total bill amount
			are interpreted to mean the service was satisfactory. Anything 
			above 25\%% means that the services were excellent! Use this
			application, and share it with your friends to spread the practice 
			of giving your waiters the royal tipping treatment!</string>

    <!-- menu options -->
    <string name="information">Information</string>
    <string name="menu_guide">Guide</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="menu_history">History</string>
    <string name="menu_share">Share</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <string name="menu_privacy">Privacy</string>

    <!-- navigation drawer accessibility options -->
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <!-- network -->
    <string name="check_network">Sorry for the delay. We\'re having trouble connecting.
        Check your internet connection and we\'ll have you tipping shortly</string>

    <!-- dialog options -->
    <string name="retry">Retry</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="okay">Okay</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>

</resources>
