<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- Application Labels -->
    <string name="app_name">Tip Calculator</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="txt_num">1</string>
    <string name="txt_percent_default">15%</string>
    <string name="txt_poor">Poor</string>
    <string name="txt_fair">Fair</string>
    <string name="txt_good">Good!</string>
    <string name="txt_great">Great!</string>
    <string name="txt_royal">Royal!</string>
    <string name="txt_service">Service:</string>
    <string name="txt_title">Tip Calculator</string>
    <string name="txt_creators">by Leonard Tatum &amp; Kazuya Shibuta</string>
    <string name="txt_bill">Bill: $</string>
    <string name="txt_tip">Tip Amount:</string>
    <string name="txt_shared">Shared By:</string>
    <string name="txt_person">Each Person Pays:</string>
    <string name="txt_total">Total Bill Amount:</string>
    <string name="txt_hint">0.00</string>
	<string name="txt_round_on">Round On:</string>
	<string name="txt_round_off">Round Off:</string>
	<string name="txt_spinner_default">Select Tip Percent</string>
    <string name="btn_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="btn_guide">Tip Guide</string>
    <string name="btn_inc">+</string>
    <string name="btn_dec">-</string>

	<!-- About -->
	<string name="copyright_year">Copyright %s, Leonard Tatum. All Rights Reserved</string>
	<string name="about_desc">This app is 100% free, created for the education, convenience
		and use of the public. There will never be in-app purchases or alternative paid versions
		of the app. To learn about other apps Leonard Tatum is working on, connect with him on social
		media or send him an email with your questions or comments. Cheers!</string>

	<!-- Privacy -->



    <!-- Guide Text -->
    <string name="txt_guide">Q1: Where don’t you tip? 
			\n\nA1: In Japan, this offering is considered offensive! 
			Because of a tip’s nature as a gift or a favor, it can be 
			perceived as an implication of servility.
			\n\nQ2: Where do you tip? 
			\n\nA2: Pretty much everywhere else! It is never embarrassing 
			to leave a tip on the table. In fact, in countries where it 
			isn’t required it is all the more appreciated. But in the US, 
			tipping is almost a mandatory requirement. This is why it is 
			important to know the rules for tipping. How much do you tip? 
			And what are reasonable tip amounts?
			\n\nQ3: How to determine the tippable total? 
			\n\nA3: Using applications like a Tip Calculator is a wonderful 
			first step to ensuring that you are issuing good tips! But here 
			are a couple unspoken rules. First, if you used any coupons or 
			discounts, calculate the tip based on how much you would have 
			paid without it. Otherwise you are punishing the server for the 
			restaurant management’s efforts to entice you through the front 
			door. For example, if you have a 2-for-1 coupon (two-fer!), you 
			may only have had to pay for half of your meal, but the waiter 
			still did the full amount of work.
			\n\nAlso, if there is a tax on your bill, you should calculate 
			the tip based on the pretax amount, since the service is not 
			really related to the tax. Additionally, the difference between 
			a tip on the total (including tax) and the pretax amount is not 
			significant.
			\n\nQ4: Is how much I tip based on the quality of service? 
			\n\nA4: The answer is yes, and no. The proper etiquette is to tip 
			regardless of terrible service, although doing so is still 
			controversial. Why pay for terrible service, right? The key is to 
			objectively judge the service, and the service alone. If the 
			food is not good, the menu is sparse, the prices are outrageous, 
			and/or the décor is appalling, all of this affects your dining 
			experience, but is not the waiter’s fault. So identify what is 
			in control of your waiter’s hands and what is not. And at the end 
			of the day, have some compassion and practice giving the benefit 
			of the doubt. If the service was not quite stellar, it may not be 
			the waiter’s fault. Exceptions are if your waiter is rude or 
			neglectful! 
			\n\nQ5: How much to tip? 
			\n\nA5: It’s great that you have an application in your hands to 
			help you determine this! No matter how poor the quality of services 
			was, leaving a tip of less than 10% will not be looked upon 
			favorably nor will it paint you in a very good light, in case of 
			future visits. Tips amounting to 18-20% of the total bill amount 
			are interpreted to mean the service was satisfactory. Anything 
			above 25% means that the services were excellent! Use this 
			application, and share it with your friends to spread the practice 
			of giving your waiters the royal tipping treatment! 
    </string>

	<!-- Menu Options -->
	<string name="information">Information</string>
	<string name="menu_guide">Guide</string>
	<string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
	<string name="menu_history">History</string>
	<string name="menu_share">Share</string>
	<string name="menu_about">About</string>
	<string name="menu_privacy">Privacy</string>

    <!-- Navigation Drawer Accessibility Options -->
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

</resources>
